RICHARD **ZOU**

0830619317

Zoulei1999@gmail.com https://www.linkedin.com/in/richard-zou-b0852990/ https://github.com/Zoulei1999

Hello my name is Richard Zou (Irish born), I am a 23 year old Computer Science graduate at TUD. I graduated in October 2022 with 2nd Class Hons, First Division, I am looking for a position in computing, but I am willing to explore different areas if the position is right. I have experience in coding languages such as Java, C, HTML, CSS, with little experience in Python and JavaScript. I have experience working at Oxfam and PhoneWatch as sales agents, where I learned how to interact with people and how to operate as a team to meet targets.

EDUCATION

2018 - 2022

BSC COMPUTER SCIENCE, TECHNOLOGICAL

UNIVERSITY DUBLIN

Institutional Honors: 2nd Class Hons, First

Division

SKILLS

- C
- Java
- Web Development
- SQL
- Python

- Customer Service.
- Communication
- Microsoft office
- React.JS
- JavaScript

PROJECTS

- ATM System The program was made using the C coding language. In this project, we had an access code that was encrypted. We had a user input that was encrypted and then compared to the access code, after that was done correctly we had a menu that the user could choose from such as deposit funds or withdraw, and exit the program.
- REACT.JS For my final year project, I developed an eCommerce store using REACT. In this project, we used tools such as material core UI and other libraries. Node.JS was used to generate the web page. This project was developed using an API that was called Commerce JS, this API managed the backend details such as product information. From this project, I learned about how to research necessary tools and how to manage time efficiently while working with a deadline.

- Sports Website After graduating university I was a bit lost in terms of direction. So In my spare
 time I made a web application in react that implemented workout that can be done at home or the
 gym. The application allows the user to select exercises that target specific muscle groups, After
 selecting a muscle group you can find exercises with video demonstrations.
- More projects can be found on my Github. Projects include said sports website(React), Blackjack game(Python), FYP(React) and other projects done in college e.g Game development in Unity.

EXPERIENCE

10/06/2018 - 06/08/2018 SALES ASSISTANT, PHONE WATCH

In this job we went to people's homes with the intention to sell people a smart security system. From this occupation I learned how to interact with people as I needed to learn how to create a demand for the product, I was selling as well as learning how to work with other people as we worked in teams for the day and we had goals that we had to try and meet. I decided to end this job as the payment for this income was paid per month based on sales and the amount I spent was not cost-efficient for me to continue as travel cost more than I earned.

15/01/2021-31/05/2021

TEAM PROJECT, Saint John of God

This was an opportunity provided by the college, in this module we were assigned a group to help develop a project that was gonna be used by the people at Saint John of God. In this module, we had a weekly meeting with the co-designers taking in their input for the design and features of the project. In this project, I took on roles such as a co-leader and took on tasks such as assigning roles and planning for team meetings. In this project, I worked on the user interface and speech recognition.

ACTIVITIES/INTERESTS

- Gaming I enjoy playing games as I use it to cooldown/relax, the main thing I enjoy is the fact that I can interact with friends on the games and talk to them.
- Reading I enjoy reading articles about things that are factual as they tell me about events happening around the world and fantasy settings.
- Gym I am currently going to the gym, to self-improve myself with the main goal to lose weight. Due to a personal issue, I gained excess weight and my goal is to return to my previous weight.